hey everybody welcome to this a2 english
listening practice video you can use
this video to practice your listening
and comprehension as i speak remember to
sign up for our one dollar listening
practice seminars at polyglossa.com and
download our free listening time podcast
so you can practice your listening
skills
[Music]
so today i'm going to talk about
complaining this might seem like a
strange topic but i think it's very
relevant because most people complain
about many things in their lives
specifically in this video i want to
talk about some of the different things
that people complain about often the
first complaint that i'm gonna talk
about is the weather depending on where
you live this might be a common
complaint in the us when people make
small talk they tend to talk about the
weather they might comment on how nice
the weather is that day or they might
talk about how terrible the weather is
it's very easy to connect with another
person when complaining about the
weather because it's an easy topic to
talk about i think this is a big reason
why people like to complain about this
topic it helps you start conversations i
sometimes complain when it's raining
especially on the weekend i love going
outside and enjoying the outdoors so
it's disappointing for me when i can't
do this
i know i shouldn't complain about things
i can't control but i do this sometimes
another thing that people love to
complain about is traffic this is one of
the worst parts about living in a big
city nowadays many people work from home
but if you work in an office you
probably have to commute to work five
days a week the verb to commute means to
travel to and from some place regularly
if you commute to work in the morning
and commute back home in the evening you
probably do this during rush hour this
is the time during the day when there
are more cars on the road if you live in
a crowded city you'll definitely hear
people complain about the traffic during
rush hour i know some people that spend
two hours in the morning and two hours
in the evening in traffic it's hard not
to complain in this situation i hate
being stuck in traffic and i definitely
complain about this sometimes alright
another thing that people complain about
is rising prices it seems like every
year life gets more and more expensive
for example in the past houses and
apartments were much cheaper than they
are now
for many young adults buying a house
seems impossible nowadays i hear people
complain about this all the time it also
seems like gas prices keep getting
higher and higher it's funny because
americans complain about this a lot but
actually gas is much more expensive in
other countries still we americans like
to complain about this
okay i saved the worst one for last in
my opinion the thing i complain about
the most is the government of course
everyone complains about corrupt
politicians and terrible presidents but
what annoys me the most is the horrible
experience you have when you use
government services i can't tell you how
many times i've been disappointed with
government services just in the last
month i've had at least three bad
experiences with the government
unfortunately this is completely normal
almost every time i use a government
service there are errors with their
website their workers are rude and it
takes them a long time to do their job
and of course the quality of their work
and their institutions is terrible for
example almost all of the students i
talked to tell me that the government
hospitals in their countries are not
good overall governments don't offer
high quality services i'm sure many of
you complain about government services
too all right now i'm going to ask you
some questions about today's video to
see if you understood number one what's
the most common topic of small talk
number two what does the verb commute
mean
and number three what's one thing that
seems to get more expensive all the time
okay remember to sign up for our one
dollar listening practice seminars and
download our free listening time podcast
so you can practice your listening
skills also subscribe to the channel
click on the bell and follow us on
instagram i'll see you next time
[Music]